Guide to the Martin Harwit papers, 1957-1987
Harwit, Martin papers, 1957-1987
- Publications
  - 65. The Far-Infrared and Submillimeter Background, J. R. Houck, B. T. Soifer, Martin Harwit and Judith L. Pipher, Ap. J. Lett, 178, L29 (1972). (Box 21)
  - 66. Direct Observations of Infrared and Submillimeter Background Radiation (Abstract), Martin Harwit, Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., in Bull. of the AAS (1972). (Box 21)
  - 67. Infrared Observations and Dyson Civilizations, M. Harwit, in "Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence," C. Sagan, ed., MIT Press, p. 381 (1973). (Box 21)
  - 68. Tachyon Bit Rates, M. Harwit, in "Communication with Extraterrestrial Intelligence, C. Sagan, ed., MIT Press, p. 395 (1973). (Box 21)
  - 69. Spectrometric Imager II, Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 12, 285 (1973). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 70. The Differential Polarization of Starlight as a Function of Distance, Stephen Lloyd and Martin Harwit, IAU Symposium #52, 203, Greenberg and Van de Hulst, eds., Reidel, Holland (1973). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 71. Photon and Magnetic Alignment of Interstellar Dust Grains, Leon W. King and Martin O. Harwit, IAU Symposium #52, 197, Greenberg and Van de Hulst, eds., Reidel, Holland (1973). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 72. Towards a More Habitable Mars -- or -- The Coming Martian Spring, J. A. Burns and Martin Harwit, Icarus, 19, 126 (1973). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 73. U. S. Patent #3,720,469, Martin Harwit, Patented March 13, 1973, "Spectrometric Imager." (Box 21)
  - 74. The Spectrometric Imager, Martin Harwit, Proceedings of 1973 Walsh Function Symposium, p. 108, (Washington) (Box 21)
  - 75. Radiation from Comets Near Neutron Stars, Martin Harwit and E. E. Salpeter, Ap. J. Lett., 186, L37 (1973). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 76. Asymmetric Hadamard Transform Spectrometers, Leon W. King, Perry G. Phillips and Martin Harwit, Proceedings of 1973 Walsh Function Symposium, p. 117 (Washington) (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 77. Book review published in Icarus, 20, 251 (1973). "Comets: Scientific Data and Missions. Proceedings of the Tucson Comet Conference," eds. G. P. Kuiper and E. Roemer, University of Arizona (1972). "The Motion, Evolution of Orbits, and Origin of the Comets: International Astronomical Union Symposium #45," eds. G. A. Chebotarev, E. I. Kazimirchak-Polanskaya and B. G. Marsden, Reidel Publishing Company, Dordrecht, Holland, Springer Verlag, New York (1972). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 78. Book review: "Gamma-Ray Astrophysics, Proceedings of a Symposium", F. W. Stecker and J. I. Trombka, eds.; NASA, Washington, D.C. (1973), Martin Harwit, Science 185, 607 (1974) (Box 21)
  - 79. Modulation Techniques in Spectrometry, Martin Harwit and John Decker, in "Progress in Optics XII," ed. E. Wolf, North Holland, p. 102 (1974). (Box 21)
  - 80. Two Asymmetric Hadamard Transform Spectrometers, Martin Harwit, Perry G. Phillips, Leon W. King and Daniel A. Briotta, Jr., Appl. Opt., 13, 2669 (1974). (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - 81. Incremental Polarization of Starlight at Different Locations in the Galaxy, Martin Harwit and Lee A. Fowler, MNRAS, 167, 227 (1974). (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - 82. A Cooled Telescope for Infrared Balloon Astronomy, C. Frederick, M. R. Jacobson, M. Harwit, NASA Symposium on Balloon Astronomy, Moffett Field, p. 81, February (1974). (Box 21)
  - 83. Observations of the Orion Nebula at 100Âµm, Dennis B. Ward and Martin Harwit, Nature, 252, 27 (1974). (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - 84. Infrared Astronomy and the Shuttle, Martin Harwit, Astronautics and Aeronautics, 12, 23 October (1974). (Box 21)
  - 85. Expected Far Infrared Polarisation of H II Regions and the Nuclei of Galaxies, Martin Harwit, 8th ESLAB Symposium, Frascati, p. 179 (1974). (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - 86. Astronomy: How Complex is the Universe?, Martin Harwit, The Arts College Observer, No. 2, Cornell University, November (1974). (Box 21)
  - 87. Gravitational Deflection of Polarized Radiation, Martin Harwit, R. V. E. Lovelace, B. Dennison, D. L. Jauncey and J. Broderick, Nature, 249, 230 (1974). (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - 88. Orientation of Planetary Nebulae Within the Galaxy, Gary Melnick and Martin Harwit, MNRAS, 171, 441 (1975). (Box 21)
  - 89. Uncertainties in the Far Infrared Absorption of Interstellar Clouds, Martin Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 199, L398 (1975). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 90. Infrared Galaxies: Evolutionary Stages of Massive Star Formation, Martin Harwit and Franco Pacini, Ap. J. Lett., 200, L127 (1975). (Box 21)
  - 91. Practical Multi-Spectrum Hadamard Transform Spectrometer, Ming Hing Tai, D. A. Briotta, Jr., N. Kamath and Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 14, 2533 (1975). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 92. Errors in Hadamard Spectroscopy or Imaging Caused by Imperfect Masks, Ming Hing Tai, Martin Harwit and Neil J. A. Sloane, Appl. Opt., 14, 2678 (1975). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 93. Detection of the (O III) 88.16 Micron Line in M17, Dennis B. Ward, Brian Dennison, George Gull and Martin Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 202, L31 (1975). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 94. Infrared Astronomy at Cornell, Martin Harwit, Alumni Brochure, Astronomy Department, Cornell University (1975). (Box 21)
  - 95. The Number of Class A Phenomena Characterizing the Universe, Martin Harwit, Quart. J. Roy. Astron. Soc., 16, 378 (1975). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 96. Masks for Hadamard Transform Optics and Weighing Designs, Neil J. A. Sloane and Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 15, 107 (1976). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 97. Communication Across the Universe, Martin Harwit, Creative Computing, March-April, p. 56 (1976). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 98. Far-Infrared Spectral Observations of M42 and M17, Dennis B. Ward, Brian Dennison, George E. Gull and Martin Harwit, Ap. J., Lett., 205, L75 (1976). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 99. Hadamard Transform Imager and Imaging Spectrometer, Roderick D. Swift, Richard B. Wattson, John A. Decker, Jr., Ralph Paganetti and Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 15, 1595 (1976). (Box 21)
  - 100. Fourier and Hadamard Transform Spectrometers: A Limited Comparison, Ming Hing Tai and Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 15, 2664 (1976). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 101. Book Review: The Study of Comets: Part 1 and Part 2. A conference held at Goddard Space Flight Center, Greenbelt, MD, October 28-November 1, 1974, ed. B. Donn, M. Mumma, W. Jackson, M. A'Hearn and R. Harrington, NASA SP-393, U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington, D.C., Icarus, 30, 435 (1977). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 102. Far-Infrared Polarization of M42, Brian Dennison, Dennis B. Ward, George Gull and Martin Harwit, Astron. J., 82, 39 (1977). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 103. Far-Infrared Spectral Observations of Venus, Mars and Jupiter, Dennis B. Ward, George E. Gull and Martin Harwit, Icarus, 30, 295 (1977). (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - 104. Discovery of Far-Infrared Sources with a New Balloon-Borne Helium-cooled. 4-meter Telescope, M. F. Campbell, P. M. Harvey, W. F. Hoffmann, M. R. Jacobson, D. B. Ward, M. O. Harwit, P. A. Aannestad, Proc. NASA Symposium on "Recent Results in Infrared Astrophysics," Ames Research Center, California (January 1977). (Box 21)
  - 105. Der Infrarote Kosmos, Martin Harwit, Umschau in Wissenschaft u. Technik, Heft 11, p. 363 (1977). (Box 21)
  - 106. Far-Infrared Spectrometry of H II Regions and the Galactic Center, D. B. Ward, G. E. Gull and M. Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 214, L63 (1977). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 107. Hadamard Transform Techniques in Spectroscopy and Imaging Spectroscopy (Abstract), M. Harwit, Infrared Physics, 17, 457 (1977). (Box 21)
  - 108. Fourier and Hadamard Transform Spectrometers: A Limited Comparison II., M. Harwit and Ming Hing Tai, Appl. Opt., 16, 3071 (1977). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 109. Molecular Transitions Observable by Infrared Techniques, Gisbert Winnewisser and Martin Harwit, "Les Spectres des Molecules Simples au Laboratoire et en Astrophysique," pp. 458-459, Liège, June 1977. (Box 21)
  - 110. Hadamard Transform Analytical Systems, Martin Harwit in "Transform Techniques in Chemistry," P. R. Griffiths, ed., Plenum Press, p. 173 (1978). (Box 21)
  - 111. Deflection of Polarized Radiation: Relative Phase Delay Technique, B. Dennison, M. Harwit, G. Melnick, T. Sato, C. Stelzried, D. Jauncey, Nature, 273, 33 (1978). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 112. Hadamard Techniques in Optics and Their Relationship to Other Multiplexing Schemes, Martin Harwit, Proc. SPIE, 148, 119 (1978). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 113. Observations of the 51.8 Micron [O III] Emission Line in Orion, G. Melnick, George E. Gull, Martin Harwit and Dennis B. Ward, Ap. J. Lett., 222, L137 (1978). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 114. Observations of [O III] 88 Micron Line Emission from H II Regions and the Galactic Center, F. W. Dain, G. E. Gull, G. Melnick, M. Harwit and Dennis B. Ward, Ap. J. Lett., 221, L17 (1978). (Box 21)
  - 115. Infrared Astronomical Background Radiation, Martin Harwit in "Infrared Astronomy," Proceedings of the NATO Advanced Study Institute held at Erice, Sicily, 9-20 July 1977, ed. Setti and G. G. Fazio, Reidel Publ. Co., pp. 173-180 (1978). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 116. Infrared Astronomical Spectroscopy, Martin Harwit in "Infrared Astronomy," Proceedings of the NATO Advanced Study Institute held at Erice, Sicily, 9-20 July 1977, ed. G. Setti and G. G. Fazio, Reidel Publ. Co., pp. 271-283 (1978). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 117. Systematic Errors in Hadamard Transform Optics, N. J. A. Sloane, M. Harwit and Ming-Hing Tai, Appl. Opt., 17, 2991 (1978) (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 118. Far-Infrared Polarization of the Kleinmann-Low Nebula in Orion, G. E. Gull, J. R. Houck, J. F. McCarthy, W. J. Forrest and M. Harwit, Astronomical Journal, 83, 1440 (1978). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 119. Observation of the 63 [O I] Micron Emission Line in the Orion and Omega Nebulae, Gary Melnick, G. E. Gull and Martin Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 227, L29 (1979). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 120. 51.8 [O III] Micron Line Emission Observed in Four Galactic H II Regions, G. Melnick, G. E. Gull and M. Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 227, L35 (1979). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 121. The Structure of the Orion Nebula: The Ionized Gas, V. Pankonin, C. M. Walmsley and M. Harwit, Astronomy & Astrophysics, 75, 34 (1979). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 122. A Search for Polarization in Interstellar Recombination Lines, M. Harwit, E. Churchwell and M. Walmsley, Astrophysics & Space Science, 66, 487 (1979). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 123. Infrared Galaxies, M. Harwit, Cornell University, Astronomy Department Alumni Brochure (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 124. Infrared Galaxies, M. Harwit, Orbit Newsletter of CRSR/NAIC, Vol. I, No. 1 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 125. On the Origin of the Grain-Size Spectrum of Interstellar Dust, Peter Biermann and Martin Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 241, L105 (1980). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 126. Astronomische Beobachtungen im Submillimeterbereich, Martin Harwit, Max-Planck-Institut für Radioastronomie Nachrichten, Heft 15 February 1980. (Box 21)
  - 127. Far-Infrared Emission Line and Continuum Observations of NGC 7027, Gary Melnick, Ray W. Russell, George E. Gull and Martin Harwit, Ap. J., 243, 170 (1980). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 128. Detection of the 157 Micron (1910 GHz) [C II] Emission from the Interstellar Gas Complexes NGC 2024 and M42, Ray W. Russell, Gary Melnick, George E. Gull and Martin Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 240, L99 (1980). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 129. Far-Infrared Polarization of the Kleinmann Low-Nebula, George E. Gull, Ray W. Russell, Gary Melnick and Martin Harwit, Astron. J., 85, 1379 (1980). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 130. Concept for a Neutrino or Antineutrino Telescope, Martin Harwit, M.N.R.A.S., 195, 481 (1981). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 131. Giant C II Halos Around H II Regions, Ray W. Russell, Gary Melnick, Scott D. Smyers, Noel T. Kurtz and Martin Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 250, L35 (1981). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 132. Monochromator-Interferometer Combination for Submillimeter Astronomical Spectrometry from Aircraft, Martin Harwit, Noel T. Kurtz, Ray W. Russell and Scott Smyers, Appl. Opt., 20, 3792 (1981). (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - 133. NASA's Airborne Astronomy Program, November 1981. (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - 134. Infrared Lines from Shocked Galactic Gases, Gary Melnick and Martin Harwit, Proceedings of SPIE -- Society of Photo-Optical Instrumentation Engineers, 280, 120 (1981). (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - 135. Monochromator-Interferometer Combination for Submillimeter Astronomical Spectrometry from Aircraft, Martin Harwit, Noel T. Kurtz, Ray W. Russell, Scott Smyers, Proceedings of SPIE, 280, 90 (1981). (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - 136. Cosmic Discovery -- The Technical Influence on Astronomy, Proceedings of the Alexander von Humboldt Foundation Bi-National Colloquium, The Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, NJ, pp. 41-56, August 1981. (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - 137. Physicists in Astronomy -- Will you join the dance?, Physics Today, pp. 172-187, November 1981. (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - 138. Upper Limits of Cosmic Infrared Background Flux as Determined by X- and Gamma-Ray Observations on M87, R. Schlickeiser and M. Harwit, A. & A., 107, 186 (1982). (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - 139. The Orion Nebula: Large-Scale Distribution of Far-Infared and Submillimeter Line Emission, Annals of the NYAS, pp. 56-63 (1982). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 140. Infrared Observations from the NASA Airborne Observatories, Proceedings of the Second ESO Infrared Astronomy Workshop, Garching, Germany, pp. 20-23, April 1982. (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 141. The Mass of Hot, Shocked CO in Orion: First Observations of the J=17 - J=16 Transition at 153 Microns, G. Stacey, N. Kurtz, S. Smyers, M. Harwit, R. Russell and G. Melnick, Ap. J. Lett., 257, L37 (1982). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 142. Progress in Airborne Infrared and Submillimetre Spectroscopy, M. Harwit, Proceedings of an ESA Workshop on "The Scientific Importance of Submillimetre Observations," held at Noordwijkerhout, The Netherlands, May 10-12, 1982, ESA SP-189, p65 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 143. Highly Excited Rotational Transitions of CO in the Orion Molecular Cloud, S. Smyers, G. Stacey, N. Kurtz and M. Harwit, poster paper presented at AAS meeting, Troy, NY, May 1982. (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 144. Far-Infrared Fine-Structure [OI] Transitions at 145 Microns in the Orion Nebula, G. Stacey, N. Kurtz, S. Smyers and M. Harwit, read at AAS meeting, Troy, NY, May 1982. (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 145. "The Significance of Far-Infrared Spectra of the Interstellar Medium," Proceedings of an ESA Workshop on "Galactic and Extragalactic Infrared Spectroscopy" held in Toledo, Spain, December 1982, eds. M. F. Kessler and J. P. Phillips, D. Reidel Publishing Co., pp. 145-166 (1984). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 146. The Acceleration of Molecular Hydrogen Clouds through Radiative Dissociation, Johannes Schmid-Burgk and Martin Harwit, Ap. J., 266, 602 (1983). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 147. The 157 Micron [C II] Emission from NGC 2024 -- Core and Halo Components, N. Kurtz, S. Smyers, R. Russell, M. Harwit and G. Melnick, Ap. J., 264, 538 (1983). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 148. Spectrophotometry of Saturn and Its Rings from 60 to 180 Microns, G. Melnick, R. Russell, T. R. Gosnell and M. Harwit, Icarus, 53, 310 (1983). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 149. The Galaxy's 157 Micron [C II] Emission: Observations by Means of a Spectroscopic Lunar Occultation Technique, G. Stacey, S. Smyers, N. Kurtz and M. Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 268, L99 (1983). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 150. Observations of the 145.5 Micron [OI] Emission Line in the Orion Nebula, G. Stacey, S. Smyers, N. Kurtz and M. Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 265, L7 (1983). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 151. Highly Excited (J = 16 to 15) Rotational Transitions of CO, at 162.8 Âµm, in the Orion Cloud, G. Stacey, N. Kurtz, S. Smyers and M. Harwit, M.N.R.A.S., 202, 25P (1983). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 152. Subillimeter Astronomy and the Problem of Star Formation, M. Harwit, Comments on Astrophysics, 10, 65 (1984). (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 153. Book Review of Karl S. Guthke's "Der Mythos der Neuzeit," M. Harwit, J. f. t. History of Astronomy, 15, 141, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - 154. Book Review of Stillman Drake's Telescopes, Tides and Tactics -- A Galilean Dialogue About the Starry Messenger and Systems of the World, and Rudolf Krämer-Badoni's Galileo Galilei, Martin Harwit, Sky and Telescope, May 1984, pp. 427-428 (Box 21)
  - 155. Far-Infrared Airborne Spectroscopy of Galactic Clouds, Martin Harwit, Third International Conference on Infrared Physics, W. Ruegsegger and F. K. Kneubühl, eds., ETH Zurich, Switzerland, July 23-27, 1984, p53 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - 156. Observational Discovery vs Theoretical Understanding, Martin Harwit, published in Serendipitous Discoveries in Radio Astronomy, ed. K. Kellermann and B. Sheets (1984), pp. 197-210 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - 157. The Course Toward Understanding in Astronomy: In and Out of the Sand Traps, Martin Harwit, National Air and Space Museum Research Report 1984, published for the National Air and Space Museum by the Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., May 1984. (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - 158. Submillimeter Observations of OH and CH in M42, Paul J. Viscuso, Gordon J. Stacey, Charles E. Fuller, Noel T. Kurtz and Martin Harwit, Ap. J., 296, 142 (1985). (Box 21)
  - 159. A Far-Infrared Cooled Grating Spectrometer for the Kuiper Airborne Observatory, E. F. Erickson, J. R. Houck, M. O. Harwit, D. M. Rank, M. R. Haas, D. J. Hollenbach, J. P. Simpson and G. C. Augason, Third International Conference on Infrared Physics, W. Ruegsegger and F. K. Kneubühl, eds., ETH Zurich, Switzerland, July 23-27, 1984. (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - 160. The 157 Âµ [CII] Luminosity of the Galaxy, Gordon J. Stacey, Paul J. Viscuso, Charles E. Fuller, Noel T. Kurtz and Martin Harwit, paper presented at the Airborne Astronomy Symposium, NASA-Ames, July 11-13, 1984; NASA Conference Publication 2353, p260 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - 161. Astronomische Entdeckungen: Nur die Technik sorgt für Fortschritt, Martin O. Harwit, Bild der Wissenschaft, pp. 155-166 (1984). (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - 162. Observations of Far-Infrared Transitions Between Excited States of OH, Paul J. Viscuso, Gordon J. Stacey, Martin Harwit, M. R. Haas, E. F. Erickson and P. B. Duffy, Ap. J., 296, 149 (1985). (Box 21)
  - 163. Book Review of George Greenstein's Frozen Star, Martin Harwit, Am. J. Phys., 53, June 1985, pp. 602-603 (Box 21)
  - 164. An FIR Cooled Grating Spectrometer for the Kuiper Airborne Observatory, E. J. Erickson, J. R. Houck, M. O. Harwit, D. M. Rank, M. R. Haas, D. J. Hollenbach, J. P. Simpson and G. C. Augason, Infrared Phys., 25, 513, 1985. (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - 165. All-Aluminum Optical System for a Large Cryogenically Cooled Far-Infrared Echelle Spectrometer, E. F. Erickson, S. Matthews, G. C. Augason, J. R. Houck, M. O. Harwit, and D. M. Rank, SPIE, 509, Cryogenic Optical Systems and Instruments (1984), pp. 129-139 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - 166. A Far Infrared Echelle Spectrometer for the Kuiper Airborne Observatory, E. F. Erickson, J. R. Houck, M. O. Harwit, D. M. Rank, M. R. Haas, D. J. Hollenbach, J. P. Simpson, G. C. Augason, and D. D. McKibbin, Airborne Astronomy Symposium, NASA Conf. Pub. 2353, Proc. of a meeting sponsored by NASA and the Astronomical Society of the Pacific held at NASA Ames Research Center July 11-13, 1984, p313 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - 167. Book Review of Jacques Merleau-Ponty's La Science de l'Univers Ã l'Ã?ge du Positivisme: Ã?tude sur les origines de la cosmologie contemporaine, J. Vrin, Paris, 1983, Martin Harwit, J. f.t. History of Astronomy, 16, 140, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - 168. Book Review of The Cambridge Atlas of Astronomy, Jean Audouze and Guy Israel's (eds.), Martin Harwit, Nature, 316, 1985, p. 432 (Box 21)
  - 169. Book Review of Albert Van Helden's Measuring the Universe, Martin Harwit, Sky and Telescope, November 1985, pp. 443-444 (Box 21)
  - 170. A New Program in the History and Philosophy of Science and Technology, Martin Harwit, Cornell University Arts & Sciences Newletter, 6, Spring 1985, p4 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - 171. The Great Observatories for Space Astrophysics, Martin Harwit and Valerie Neal, prepared under the auspices of the NASA Astrophysics Division, 1985. (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - 172. Is IRAS Cirrus Cloud Emission Largely Fine-Structure Radiation Martin Harwit, James R. Houck, and Gordon J. Stacey, Nature, 319, 646 (1986). (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - 173. How Many More Discoveries in the Universe Martin Harwit and Roger Hildebrand, Nature, 320, 724 (1986). (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - 174. Book review of Birth and Infancy of Stars, Robert Lucas, Alain Omont, and Raymond Stora, (eds.), Martin Harwit Science, 231, 1201 (1986). (Box 21)
  - 175. Book review of Michael Rowan-Robinson's The Cosmological Distance Ladder, Martin Harwit, Science, 230, 163 (1985). (Box 21)
  - 176. Book review of Early History of Cosmic Ray Studies: Personal Reminiscences with Old Photographs, (eds.) Yataro Sekido and Harry Elliot, ISIS 77, 730 (1986). (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - 177. Statement of Martin Harwit for Space Science: Past, Present and Future, Hearings before the Subcommittee on Space Science and Applications of the Committee on Science and Technology, U.S. House of Representatives, Ninety-Ninth Congress, Oct. 8-10, 1985, pp. 69-179 (Box 23)
  - 178. Space Astronomy -- An Historical Perspective, Martin Harwit, Congressional Lecture Series #1, 1986. (Box 21)
  - 179. The Most Luminous Far-Infrared Extragalactic Sources, M. Harwit, J. R. Houck, B. T. Soifer, and G. G. C. Palumbo, Ap. J., 315, 28 (1987). (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - 180. Hinge Spectrometer: A Grating Fabry-Perot Instrument for Far- Infrared/Submillimeter Spectroscopy in Space, Martin Harwit, Paul J. Viscuso, Gordon Stacey, and Charles Fuller, Appl. Opt., 26, 669 (1987). (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - 181. Regularly Pulsed Neutrinos from Supernova SN1987A? Martin Harwit, Peter L. Biermann, Hinrich Meyer, and Ira Wasserman, Nature, 328, 503 (1987). (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - 182. Questions on Star Formation -- and Observations to Answer Them, Martin Harwit, in Space Astronomy & Solar System Exploration: Preceedings of Summer School held at Alpbach, Austria, July 29 - August 8, 1986, (ESA SP-268, May 1987 P 25) (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - 183. Extremely Luminous Far-Infrared Sources (ELFS), Martin Harwit, James R. Houck, B. Thomas Soifer, Giorgio G. C. Palumbo, Star Formation in Galaxies Conference, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, California, June 16-19, 1986. NASA Conference Publication 2466, P387, 1987. (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - 184. Radio Measurements in the Fields of Gamma-Ray Sources. III. The Star Formation Region -Ophiuchi, R. Schlickeiser, M. Harwit, M. E. Ã?zel, W. Sieber, S. M. Younis, and A. Schinckel, submitted to A. & A. (main journal). 1988 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - 185. An attempt to Model the Growth of Understanding in Astronomy, Martin Harwit, Proccedings of the Vatican Observatory Conference Held in Castel Gandolfo 1 to 9 July 1985, Ed. W.R. Stoeger, S.J., Specola Vaticana, 1987, P89 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - 186. The Next Twenty-Five Years, Proceedings of the Vatican Observatory, Martin Harwit, Conference Held in Castel Gandolfo, 1 to 9 July, 1985, Ed. W.R. Stoeger, S.J., Specola Vaticana, 1987, P566 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - 187. The Promise of Astrophysical Observations Conducted From Space, Martin Harwit, J. o. t. British Interplanetary Society, 41, 17, 1988. (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - 188. Extremely Luminous Far-Infrared Colliding Galaxies -- Computation of Colliding-Galaxy Luminosity Function, Martin Harwit and Charles E. Fuller, Astrophysical Journal 328, 111, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - 189. The Next Decades of Space Astronomy, Martin Harwit, Proceedings of the ESA workshop, held at Alpbach, Austria, Summer 1987 (ESA SP-283, May 1988, P205) (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - 190. Conference Summary, Comets to Cosmology, Ed. A. Lawrence, Lecture Notes in Physics 297, Springer-Verlag, 1988, P385 (Box 21, Folder 41)